

**ADDRESS:** 

28A Alto, Sillavan Way, Salford, M3 6GA

**PHONE:** 

07766 165 724

**EMAIL:** 

jordankay295@gmail.com

#### **Personal Profile**

I'm a junior developer with a passion for solving problems with efficient solutions. My professional experience is in digital marketing through generating online sales in a variety of industries. After two years of digital marketing I'm looking for a new challenge in something that sparks my creativity, by becoming a developer. Since September 2020, my time has been dedicated to learning web development and building my portfolio, jordankay.me.

My developer skills are self-taught, alongside guidance from friends in the web development community. I have experience with the following technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Sass, React, Bootstrap, Git, Yarn and Firebase. My personal development has progressed so rapidly as a result of my love of learning new skills and the creative elements in building a project. I jump into problems feet first, learn quickly when working through a project, and I'm happy to have a go before asking for help. I'm looking for a role that will challenge me technically and creatively, honing my developer skills in a team environment.

# **Work Experience**

# **Digital Marketing Manager**

June 2019 - August 2020

## MH Hair & Beauty

MH Hair & Beauty is a small online beauty retailer selling through Amazon and eBay. With a focus on end of lines, discontinued items and multipack products, the business has found a niche demand in a very competitive marketplace. As the digital marketing manager, my role was very hands-on through planning and delivering the online marketing strategies to maximise revenue. During my time there I was able to:

- Quadruple return on ad spend, year-on-year
- Research, plan and implement new product lines
- Reduce average cost-per-click by 35%
- Analyse market trends to make data-driven decisions

# Account Executive July 2018 – June 2019

#### **Dream Agility**

Dream Agility is an AdTech company that develops software to boost online advertising campaigns using AI and Machine Learning. As well as licensing software, Dream Agility also work as an agency for clients requiring exceptional digital marketing expertise. I worked as an account executive managing paid search performance across a range of clients including Samsung and Chemist Warehouse. During my time there I was able to:

- Double conversion value for Chemist Warehouse year-on-year
- Increase sales 27% year-on-year for Anchor Pumps
- Co-ordinate with the developer team to create and launch a SaaS paid search product
- Communicate effectively with a variety of stakeholders to produce a cohesive marketing strategy

As a self-employed Editor I worked independently editing video projects for online content creators. It was important that I maintained focus and momentum, working alone to meet client specifications and deadlines. The process also required me to acquire self-taught skills across the Adobe product range e.g. video cutting, visual effects, colour correction and sound design.

#### **Barman**

September 2015 – February 2016

### **Spread Eagle Public House**

I worked as a part-time barman in a busy pub and developed my interpersonal skills through extensive interaction with customers. The role required me to be able to talk to anyone, answer their questions and meet their requests, ensuring everyone left with a smile.

JK Ltd: July 2012 – August 2015

During school holidays I was employed by a housing developer as a labourer to move materials and assist the tradesmen when required.

#### **Education**

### BSc Business and Economics 2:2, University of Salford

Modules included; Data Analysis, Statistics, Accounting, Econometric Analysis, Game Theory, Macroeconomics and Microeconomics. I am very interested in new technologies and particularly enjoyed researching and writing a study on Tesla and their impact on the American automotive industry. I also organised and led statistics workshops creating discussion forums, enabling other students to collaborate.

### **Bacup and Rawtenstall Grammar School**

A level: Economics (A), Mathematics (B), Chemistry (B)

### **Bury Grammar School**

GCSEs: 10 A\* - C (Maths A\*, English Language A, German A)

### **Skills**

I have strong quantitative skills; enjoy working with statistics and data and have experience of verifying and validating data. My keen attention to detail has been a core pillar in finding opportunities for growth whilst managing accounts in paid search, and the ability to problem solve effectively has maintained client satisfaction. I have excellent written and verbal communication enabling me to work effectively with a variety of stakeholders and can work independently, planning and organising my own workload.

My work has also trained me to be proficient in the MS Office suite of applications: Word, Powerpoint, Outlook and advanced Excel skills (pivot tables, LOOKUP and MATH functions).

#### **Interests**

I am interested in computer hardware and enjoy building computers in addition to coding, cooking, playing video games and skiing every winter. I enjoy playing poker and at university was a founding member of The Poker Society, which grew to over 30 members, hosting weekly tournaments, for all skill levels.